女士们先生们走过路过不要错过
Ladies and gentlemen,step around,,gather around.
我让你们轻轻松松挣点小钱
Let me show you a way to make a,little easy money.
明白我在说什么吗?
Understand what I'm sayin'?
这些是黑牌 不要盯着黑牌
These are the blacks,don't follow the blacks.
你得盯着皇后牌 知道为什么吗?
You want to follow the queen--know why?
因为它是红牌 也就说她很辣!
'Cause she's red,and that means she is hot!
所以你得盯着皇后牌
So you gotta find the queen.
今日开张第一把免费 谁想来?
The first of the day is free to play.,Who wants to play?
你似乎有兴趣啊 兄弟 要不要来一把?
You look interested,my man.,You want to step on up?
快啊 谁想来玩玩?
Come on, now,who wants to play?
你怎么样 甜心 你很漂亮 来试试
What about you, sweetie?,You're cute, come on up.
漂亮姑娘总能赢钱 你看起来走大运 来
Cute girls win money all day.,You look lucky, now.
盯着皇后 开始了,盯着皇后 盯着皇后
Follow the queen,here we go.,Follow the queen,follow the queen.
她不是Helen Mirren 但这皇后为你准备,(Helen Mirren 凭英国女皇获Oscar影后)
She ain't no helen mirren,,but this queen is for you.
哪个是 哪个是?
Which one is it? Which one is it?
- 就是这个,- 就是这个?
- It's right there.,- Right there?
新手运气好
Beginner's luck.
要解女人心 还需女人清,要寻皇后处 还求女士行
I'll tell you what,takes a woman to know a woman,,takes a lady to find a queen.
给你...喔...
There you go--oh...
想要翻倍吗?
want to double up?
- 好吧,- 我们得冒险 我们得冒险
- All right.,- We gonna chance it,we gonna chance it.
好了 开始 开始 你只要找到皇后就可以了
All right, here we go,here we go.,All you gotta do is find your queen.
你赢不了第二次 赢不了的
You will not win again.You will not win again.
好了 来了 来了...
All right, here we go, here we go--
找到皇后 找到皇后 她在哪儿?
find your queen.,Find your queen. Where is she?
嘣--你能找出来吗?
Boom--can you find her?
- 这个就是,- 这一个?
- Right there.,- This one?
我的天 她快吃定我了
Oh, my gosh,she is killin' me.
她把我的房租钱都赢走了
She is taking all my rent.
谁想在这个幸运星姑娘后面来?
Anybody else want to get behind,the good-luck girl?
- 我来,- 你来? 你是下一个
- I can do it.,- You can do it?You're next.
给我个机会把钱赢回来,要不然我就得露宿街头了
Give me a chance to get my money back,or I'm gonna be out here sleeping on the street.
开始 准备好了 最后一次 我要认真了
Here we go.Ready?This is the last time.,I'm not messin' no more.
你把我的钱都赢光了 姑娘
You're taking all my money, girl.
开始 最后一次机会
Here we go.This is your last chance.
最户一次了 盯着皇后 盯着皇后
***Follow the queen,follow the queen.
她在哪里?
Where's she at?
只给你看一次 她在那里 嘣嘣嘣
I'll show you one time.,There she is, boom, boom, boom.
选一张
Pick a card.
我不能决定
I can't decide.
什么意思? 选张牌就好 做出抉择
What do you mean?,Just pick a card,just make a decision.
- 我不能决定,- 每张牌都有可能
- I can't decide.,- Any card will do.
- 左 右 中?,- 我不 我不知道
- Left, right, center?,- I don't--I don't know.
- 你要右边这张吗?!,- 我不知道
- Do you want the right?!,- I don't know.
- 左边的? 中间的?,- 我不知道 我...
- The left?The center?,- I don't know. I--
那就让开 给别人玩
move out the way,let somebody else play then.
我不能决定...我不能...
I can't decide.I--I can'T.
- 要投硬币吗?,- 我这是怎么了?
- You want to flip a coin for it?,- What's wrong with me?
-=怪杰医生豪斯=-,第三季 第20集,"House Training"
House M.D.,Season 03 Episode 20
我这辈子最恐怖的30秒
scariest 30 seconds of my life.
我什么都做不了
I couldn't do anything.
就好像脑袋不能运转了一般
It's like I couldn't move inside my head.
这叫意志缺失 无法做决定或行使意志
It's called abulia,the inability to,make a decision or exercise will.
还会再发生吗?
Is it gonna happen again?
这是T.I.A.的一部分--,短暂性脑缺血发作
It's part of a T.I.A.--,A transient is chemic attack.
血液不能被输送到你额叶的一部分
Blood was cut off to a section,of your frontal lobe.
- 是不是就像中风什么的?,- 有一点
- Is that like a stroke or something?,- A little.
你最近服了什么药?
What drugs have you taken recently?
没有磕药
No drugs.
毒素是另一种可能
Toxins are another possibility.
比如你可能在工作时暴露在毒素下
You might have been exposed to,something at work, for instance.
现在没什么真的工作
No real job right now.
接触到毒素会积累并潜伏一段时间
Exposure can build up over time,and lie dormant for a while.
- 你上次工作是做什么的?,- 在宠物商店
- What was your last job?,- Pet store.
- 国外宠物?,- 热带鱼
- Exotic pets?,- Tropical fish.
- 在那之前呢?,- 失业
- And before that?,- Unemployment.
在那之前我电话推销杂志
And before that,I sold subscriptions on the phone.
再在那之前 失业
And before that,unemployment.
在那之前我在牛仔裤店干活
Before that I worked at jeans gone wild.
在那之前 失业
Before that,unemployment.
在那之前 我遛狗
Before that,I walked dogs.
而在那之前...
And before that...
无法自由抉择
loss of free wilL.
我喜欢
I like it.
说不定可以咨询一下托马斯·阿奎那,(中世纪哲学家与神学家)
Maybe we can get thomas aquinas in,for a consult.
是什么导致了短暂性脑缺血发作?
What caused the T.I.A.?
动脉没问题 没有血栓
Arteries are clear.No sign of a clot.
说不定溶解了 最可能是心脏的问题
Could've dissolved.Most likely came,from her heart.
应该做个气泡分析
We should do a bubble study.
28岁的不磕药 不太可能有血栓
clots are unlikely in a 29-year-old,who's not on the pill.
可能是毒品导致的脑血管痉挛
It's probably a vaso-spasm caused by drugs.
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
她一直换工作,可能是注意力不足过动症
She goes from job to job.,Maybe there's come kind of A.D.D. Here.
可以精确找到神经学上的...
Help us pinpoint where the neurological--
她一直换工作 是因为她是个碰瓷的
she goes from job to job,because she's a scam artist.
她干到失业为止
She works just long enough,to qualify for unemployment,
被炒 然后就吸毒
then gets fired and gets high.
我还是觉得不是吸毒
I still don't think it's drugs.
你检查了传染病吗?
Did you check for infection?
腰椎穿刺显示没问题 没有发烧,白细胞计数正常
lp showed nothing.No fever,,white blood count is normal.
可能接触到毒素
Could be toxic exposure.
你不是一直说肯定是吸毒的嘛
You're the one always saying,it must be drugs.
你觉得她是少数民族 就一定会嗑药?
You figure he's a minority,,she must be stoned?
你知道我没有那...
You know that's not what I--
- 她看起来是个好姑娘,- 你都还没见过她!
- she seems like a nice girl.,- you haven't met her!
她15岁就怀孕 从高中退学
She was pregnant at 15,,dropped out of high school.
她可会折腾了
She's a real overachiever.
拜托 公平点,她孩子死于婴儿猝死综合症
come on, cut her some slack--,her baby died of sids.
这不是一个好姑娘受了创伤的浪漫故事
this isn't some romantic story,about a nice girl scarred by tragedy.
她是个受到创伤的嗑药碰瓷者
She's a drug-using scam artist,scarred by tragedy.
另一面来说 她的毒素筛检结果出来了,她没问题
On the other hand,her tox-screen,just came back.She's clean.
你在浪费我的时间 他在浪费--
You're wasting my time.He's waste--
第二位前任Wilson太太来索钱?
second ex-mrs. Wilson want money?
我已经不在付赡养费了
I am no longer paying alimony.
她想要独立 所以考了房产经纪人执照
She wanted her independence,,so she got her realtor's license.
市场低迷 她却想赚钱
Market's doing badly,she wants money.
市场低迷 她得搬进单人公寓
The market's doing badly,,she's moving into a condo.
- 她要--,- 她要我来养Hector
- She wants--,- she wants me to take hector.
- 泳池清洁工?,- 狗
- Pool boy?,- Dog.
没兴趣了
No longer interested.
我们度蜜月时买的
We got him on our honeymoon.
所以我就是父母之一 但我不能养他
So I'm, like,the other parent.,But I can't take him.
酒店不允许养狗 再说我一直都在这儿
My hotel doesn't allow dogs.,Besides,I'm always here.
我邀请Cuddy礼拜四去看一场戏剧
I asked cuddy to a play thursday.
噢 你...好吧
Oh, you--okay.
她说她没空
She said she was busy.
而你不相信她 所以你买通了清洁工
And you didn't believe her,,so you bribed a janitor,
侵入她的电脑 检查她的预约...
broke into her computer,,checked her appointments--
我是试探着问她的
I asked her as a test.
如果她答应了你会知道什么?
What would you have learned,if she'd said yes?
会明白奴役盲从
A lot about bondage.
她对我没空 对你却有空
She's busy for me,,but not for you.
她对戏剧本身没兴趣 她对你有兴趣
E's not interested in the play qua play,,she's interested in you.
不 我不要再次困在你的神经旋风里
No, I'm not getting sucked into the vortex,of your insanity again.
不要在课上给我传字条,不要让我邀请她去舞会
Don't pass me notes in class,,don't tell me to ask her to the prom.
你没法把她当成普通朋友,你在勾引她
You cannot see her socially.,You're leading her on.
我会考虑的..,在我带她去看Hockney作品展之后
I'll consider that,after I take her,to the hockney exhibit.
在礼拜四 明白了吧 她的确没空
On thursday.See, she is busy.
这不是约会
It's not a date.
她很享受戏剧 我很享受于她能享受
She enjoyed the play.,I enjoyed her enjoying the play.
她工作的很辛苦 能让她放松一下也好
The woman works hard.It's nice,to see her relax.
这享受来享受去的 是出于博爱?
So all this enjoying,is an act of charity?
我都留着收据退税呢
I'm keeping the receipts for tax purposes.
不能做愚蠢决定的生活还有什么意思?
What's life without the ability,to make stupid choices?
她需要她的自由意志
She needs her free will.
在她不能决定是否要呼吸前 找出病因
Find out why her brain froze before she,can't decide to take her next breath.
你去找毒素 你做气泡分析
You find the toxins,you run the bubble study.
什么都不会找到 但我需要霸占办公室
You won't find anything,,but I'll get the office to myself.
网上有一大堆黄片呢
There's a lot of porn piling upon the internet.
它们可不会自动下载
Doesn't download itself.
- Eric...Eric!,- 你好 Foreman先生
- Eric...eric!,- Hello, mr. Foreman.
- Chase医生 你好吗?,- 好啊
- Dr. Chase, how are you?,- Good.
- 你能碰上我们可真走运...,- 你到外面等我吧
- You're lucky you caught us--,- I'll meet you outside.
嗨 爸爸 我在赶路
Hey, dad.Uh, I've gotta go.
你怎么来了 没出问题吧?
Why are you here?Everything okay?
一如既往地好
Good as ever.
我们住在附近一家酒店里
We're staying at a hotel down the street.
你不会把妈妈带来吧?
You didn't bring mom with you?
再过几天就是她60岁生日了
It's gonna be her 60th birthday,in a few days.
我知道...我们在电话里说过了
I know--we talked about it on the phone.
你说你回不了家
You said you couldn't come home.
你不必过来的
You didn't have to come.
你已经八年没回家了
You haven't been home in eight years.
她应当见见你...
She should see you...
在她忘记你是谁之前
while she still knows who you are.
爸爸 我和她讲过电话了
Dad, I've talked to her on the phone.
她只是...偶尔的...记得我
She only knows who I am...sometimes.
偶尔...也很重要
Sometimes...is important.
你和你爸怎么了 你不知道他要过来?
So what's up with your dad?,Didn't know he was gonna be in town?
不知道
No.
这么老的建筑物到处都可能有毒素发散
A building this old,,there could be toxic exposure anywhere.
石棉 霉 墙纸上的染料
Asbestos, mold,the coloring agents,in the old wallpaper.
或者...可能是毒品
Or it could be drugs.
我以为我们已经排除...
I thought we ruled out--
清白的毒素筛检说明毒品没有导致T.I.A.
clean tox-screen means,drugs didn't cause the T.I.A.
毒品可能和毒素结合在了一起
Drugs can be laced with toxic substances.
砷 老鼠药
Arsenic, rat poison.
毒品被排除体外后 毒素留下了
The drugs wash out of her system,,the toxins stick around.
接触毒素有无数种方式
Exposure could come about any number of ways.
不能假设是使用了毒品
There's no reason to assume it was,through drug use.
那是肯定 除非找到了用过的吸管
Absolutely,except for the crack pipe.
我会检查她的血液来找砷和老鼠药
I'll test her blood for arsenic and rat poison.
是啊 你喜欢这样 不是吗?
Yeah, you'd like that,wouldn't you?
你爸爸叫你一起吃晚饭了吗?
Your dad asked you out for dinner?
我来检查 你好好去陪你的家人
I'll do the tests.,You're stuck with your family.
你喜欢Hockney?,(英国著名波普艺术家 同性恋者)
You like hockney?
你听说了啊
You heard about that.
波普艺术还是裸男情色画作?
The pop stuff or the venezuelan pictures?
这问题真贼
That's a trick question.
是啊 你想不到这怎么会贼
Yes, but you have no idea how it's a trick.
我喜欢艺术 我接受新事物 有错吗?
I like art.I'm open to new things.,What's the problem?
你宁愿去画廊看不存在的情色画
You're going to a gallery to see venezuel,an pictures that don't exist,
也不肯跟我其看戏 为什么?
but you won't go to a play with me.Why?
House 为什么我的社交生活突然重要起来了?
House,why is my social life suddenly red hot?
刚才我还和爱斯基摩人一起驾雪橇,如同往常
One minute I'm mushing along with,the huskies,as usual,
突然之间 全球变暖
and suddenly it's global warming.
你看到别人从沙盒里捡了一个玩具
You think you saw somebody else,pick up a toy from the sandbox,
突然之间你也想要了
and suddenly you want it.
所以你拒绝我?
Is that why you said no?
也许我只是要个朋友,而我觉得Wilson是个安全的选择
Maybe I just want a friend,,and I thought wilson was a safe choice.
我不安全 酷
I'm not safe?Cool.
James wilson永远都不会是安全选择
James wilson is never the safe choice.
我们是去画廊,不是去结婚
We're going to a gallery,,we're not getting married.
当然了 你现在这么说,到头来都会和他结婚的
Sure, you say that now.,He always marries 'em in the end.
是Eric吗? Eric!
is that eric?Eric!Oho ho ho.
喔 宝贝 宝贝
Oh, baby, baby.
我要去找到你高中毕业时,我给你拍的那张照片
I wanted to find that picture I took,at your high school graduation.
我把它重新装裱了
I had it re-framed.
就在行李里头 但我记不清放哪了
It's in one of these suitcases,,but I don't know--
等下再给我看好了
you could show it to me later.
你爸想知道你有没有坚持做祈祷
Your father wants to know if you've been praying.
你没必要非得这样子说吧
You don't have to just,come out with it like that.
我只想知道你开不开心
But I only want to know if you're happy.
开心 我很好
Sure, I'm okay.
你喜欢这里么 有一群朋友?
You like it here,you have friends?
是啊 一切都很好 妈
Yeah,everything's great, mom.
所以我把照片给你带来了
That's why I brought the picture for you.
我记得你小的时候
I remember when you were little,
喜欢盯着数学书的背面看
you liked to look in the back of the math book
因为你知道虽然开头弄不懂
because you knew even though,it made no sense then,
到学年末 你就全部搞懂了
by the end of the year,,you'd understand it all.
所以你把照片带来了?
That's why you brought the picture?
你习惯向前看 瞧下自己能走多远
You wanted to look ahead,to see how far you'd go.
现在你长大了
Now you're a grown man,
我想你或许想回头看看,自己已经走了多远
I thought you might like to look back,to see how far you've come.
一切都豁然开朗了 是不是?
It all makes sense now,doesn't it?
- 这不是我的,- 在你橱里找到的
- That isn't mine.,- It was in your closet.
这是我过去一个室友的
It belongs to this guy who used,to live with me.
你最好告诉他他有砷中毒
You might want to let him know,he's got arsenic poisoning.
我们需要他的头发检查一下中毒程度
We should get a sample of his hair,so we can see the extent--
但是我不--我不嗑药的
But I don't do--I don't do drugs.
准备休克急救 呼吸骤停
Get a crash cartin here!Respiratory arrest!
你肯定不是砷中毒引起的
Are you sure it isn't from the arsenic?
Foreman医生说我中毒了
Dr. Foreman said I was poisoned.
你的头发里只有极少量的砷
Your hair showed only a trace amount.
不足以对肺造成如此程度的损伤,现在你要保持不动
Not enough to damage your lungs like this.,We need you to stay still now.
从肺尖开始有六毫米切口
Six-millimeter cuts starting at the apices.
想跟你说下 万一你回心转意,我还在空窗期
Also, I just wanted to let you know,should you,change your mind,I'll be available.
你还没有听厌我的回答?
Aren't you getting tired of hearing me say it?
我绝无意和你约会
I have no intention of going out with you,
和你做爱 任何工作以外的事都不行
of having sex with you--of doing anything,with you except work.
没必要大惊小怪的,我只想跟你提一下来着
We don't have to makea big deal about it.,I just thought I'd let you know.
我觉得周二是个提起话题的好日子
I've decided tuesdays would be a good day,to do that.
你不是突然间爱上我
You did not suddenly fall in love with me.
你是在找寻某些东西 而我恰好--
You were looking for something,,and I happened to be--
Cameron 没关系的
cameron.It's fine.
没必要纠缠这个话题
No need to go on about it.
全面扫描肺底部
I'm dancing through the lung bases.
- 要把这件事放下,- 了解
- We need to put this behind this.,- Understood.
- 但是你老提起,- 不肯停 还在说的是你
- But you keep bringing it up.,- You're the one who's still talking.
我不对你强求什么
Look, I'm not demanding anything from you.
我没有尾随到你家里,不报期望
I'm not following you home.,I've got no expectations.
每周一次礼貌的提醒不能算是骚扰吧
A gentle, polite reminder once a week,is hardly stalking.
肺舌外有肿块
There's a mass...just outside the lingular.
活检显示血管壁内存有白细胞
Biopsy shows there are white blood cells,in the walls of the blood vessels.
它们本不该穿过蹦床的
They're not supposed to get past the bouncers.
肯定是自体免疫病 淋巴之类的问题
It's gotta be autoimmune--,something lymphocytic.
白细胞攻击躯体自身
The white blood cells are attacking,her own body.
剩下的问题就是哪种自体免疫病?
Only question is what kind of autoimmune?
- 是哪一种无关紧要,- 是哪一种很有关系
- It doesn't matter what kind.,- It always matters what kind.
- 治疗总是用类固醇,- 治疗一成不变的无聊
- Treatment's always steroids.,- Treatment is always boring.
诊断--
Diagnosis--
好吧 如果影响到了大血管
okay, it's affecting the larger blood vessels.
肯定是巨细胞动脉炎,给她用类固醇
It's gotta be giant cell arteritis.,I'll start her on steroids.
如果影响到了小血管,肯定是狼疮性血管炎
It's affecting the smaller blood vessels.,Gotta be lupusvasculitis.
给她用类固醇 如果影响到了--
I'll start her on steroids.It's affecting--
好的 明白了
yeah, got it.
- 给她用类固醇,- 好主意
- Start her on steroids.,- Good idea.
说了很无聊的
Told you it was boring.
- 我要出去下,- 为什么?
- I gotta go out.,- Why?
Wilson有个约会
Wilson's got a date.
天花板有15尺高,开放式布局
it's got 15-foot ceilings,,it's an open floor plan.
我不敢相信你会打电话给我
You know, I can't believe you called me.
嘿 我需要间公寓
Hey, I need a condo.
你和Wilson的初次约会不就在这附近?
Didn't you and wilson have,your first date around here?
你竟然记得我们初次约会的地方?
you remember where our first date was?
- 我以为你不会留心的,- 怎么会?
- I didn't think you were paying attention.,- Really?
他是我最铁的朋友
He's my best friend.
我们第一次约会是在波士顿
Our first date was in boston.
和我印象中的地方不是很近
Not quite as close to here as I remembered.
- 但我们不是来谈他的,- 绝对不是
- But we're not here to talk about him.,- Absolutely not.
你得好好看下厨房
Wait'll you see the kitchen.
全花岗岩台面
All-granite countertops.
既然那时候我没留心,和他约会感觉如何?
Since I wasn't paying attention back then,,what was it like dating him?
- 这是Hockney作品展?,- 不知怎么回事?
- So this is hockney?,- No.I don't know what happened.
我肯定你也迷糊
I'm sure you don't.
我还不知道你的格调这么包容万象
I never knew your tastes were so eclectic.
哦 Hockney作品展在4月20日结束,我记成5月20日了
Oh, the hockney exhibit finished on april 20th.,I thought it was may 20th.
好吧 我的错
Okay, my bad.
这不是个适合约会的地方
This is not somewhere I'd bring someone,on a date.
明显这也不是约会
N-not that this is a date,obviously.
我刚才在想...
I was just thinking...
他现阶段正在创作一些风景画
he's doing landscapes on multiple canvases now,
带有宁静的意味 而你一直这么忙
and they're kinda peaceful.,And you're always so busy.
我想以前从没看过你尴尬的样子
I don't think I've ever,seen you embarrassed before.
哦 那本来就不是约会
oh, it was never a date.
我刚结束一段糟糕的恋情,他说我们可以出去 作为朋友
I was coming off a bad relationship,,and he said we could go out as friends.
就是看看戏 去博物馆
You know, just go see plays,,go to a museum.
- 我以为你不喜欢特伦顿 (新泽西州府),- 爱死了
- I didn't think you liked trenton.,- Love it.
所以他说不是约会 但过后骗你上床
So he'd say it's not a date,,but then he'd jump you.
哦 不 他是认真的
Oh, no, he meant it.
{\fn方正准圆_GBK\fs12\bord1\shad0\4a&H00&\fscx90\fscy110James wilson,
James Wilson
无微不至照顾你所需
carefully calibrating his level of,protectiveness for your individual needs.
- 你是把Wilson比成卫生巾?,- 没有
- Did you just compare wilson to a tampon?,- No.
这让人心生爱意,他是真心诚意想做个朋友
It was very endearing.,He really just wanted to be a friend.
所以我骗他上床了
So i jumped him.
卧室在那头
The bedroom's through here.
真是个烂创意
that's such a bad idea.
这样子没可能不对大肠造成损伤
There is no way that won't cause damage,to the large intestine.
你还留在这里是想折磨我么?
Are you keeping us here to torture me?
- 这是单车打气筒?,- 就是啊
- Is that a bicycle pump?,- That's what I'm saying.
好像走入一个难以脱身的陷阱
It's like walking into a sticky trap.
一旦你是关注的焦点 会上瘾的
Once you're the focus of all that attention,,it's addictive.
厨房里的灶足够大厨用的
This unit's kitchen has got a chef's oven.
我经常做菜的 继续
I cook a lot.Go on.
情感上的事情让你深陷其中
It's the emotional stuff that really sucks you in.
他就是身披铠甲光彩夺目的骑士
He's just so "knight in shining armor,"you know?
总在那里守护你 直到有一天他不在了
Always there to support you,,until one day he's not.
但那时 你已无法自拔
But by then,you're hooked.
你能不能劝他照顾狗狗?
Hey,do you think that you could talk to him,about taking the dog?
他是Hector唯一能处得来的人
He's the only one that hector really,gets along with.
我们是来谈房子的 不是Wilson
we're here to talk real estate,not wilson.
就是说如果在两情相悦前你们就上床了
So you're saying if you'd actually had sex,before you connected emotionally,
你会容易解脱
you'd have gotten over him.
是啊 怪怪的 对么?
Oh, yeah.It seems weird, right?
因为和James做爱真是美妙极了
'Cause sex with james was fantastic.
没人比他更卖力去满足女人
Nobody works harder to give a woman,what she wants.
有六个燃火点
It's got six burners.
- 说那个炉灶,- 明白了
- The chef's oven.,- Right.
感觉怎么样了?
How you feeling?
那不是我的吸管
That wasn't my crack pipe.
你说过了 你感到疲劳了?
You told me.Are you tired?
我只是用它吸过几次
I just took a hit off it a couple times.
小乐一下又有何妨?
What's wrong with having a little fun?
你的私事与我无关
Your personal life is none of my business.
你不喜欢我 是不是?
You don't like me,though, do you?
那是你的想像
That's your imagination.
各式各样的吸毒我都见过
I've seen every kind of drug abuse.
无意冒犯 你可没有脱颖而出
No offense,but you don't even,stand out in the pack.
我敢说 你赚钱的同时 脾气也养刁了
I'm betting you got money,the same place you got attitude.
戒了酒和减掉体重的人
You know, people who quit drinking,,and people who lose weight,
瞧不起没能做到的人
they think they're better,than the people that couldn'T.
因为你脱离了 就以为没能做到的人...
And because you got out of the projects,,you think that anybody who didn't
软弱而且愚蠢
Is weak and stupid.
我没有对你妄加评判 吸口气
I'm not judging you.Take a breath.
你我唯一的差别,只是我做了些糟糕的决定
The only difference between me and you,is that I made some bad decisions,
而你做了些正确的
and you made some good ones.
你一生每一天都在做糟糕的决定
You make bad decisions every day of your life.
不要再吸毒 不要再耽于享乐,回到学校 拿到中学毕业证书
Stop doing drugs,stop having fun.,Go back to school and get your ged.
是啊 哪来的钱呢?
Yeah, where's the money coming from?
制度不是为我这样的人建的
The system's not set up for people like me.
- 你盯着什么看?,- 你的眼睛
- What are you staring at?,- Your eyes.
你的巩膜有黄染
There's yellow in the sclera.
她的肝脏正在衰竭
Her liver's failing.
如不进行移植 她会在48小时内死亡
Without a transplant,,she'll be dead in the next 48 hours.
应该加大免疫抑制剂用量
We should increase her immunosuppressants,
进行更针对性的治疗 增用氨甲蝶呤
and target more specifically--add methotrexate.
是 就多做些无用功吧
yeah, let's do more of what's not working.
这不是自体免疫病
This is not an autoimmune disease.
她的白细胞正在攻击自身 这就是自体免疫病
Her white blood cells are attacking her body.,That's autoimmune.
先是大脑 然后是肺部 现在是肝脏
first brain, then lungs, now liver.
都在恶化 都在两天之内
All getting worse and all in two days.
病情进展得太快
It's moving too fast.
肯定是癌症 淋巴瘤样肉芽肿病
It's gotta be cancer.,Lymphomatoid granulomatosis.
即使按我们的标准讲也算罕见,但符合她的症状
It's rare even by our standards,,but it fits her symptoms.
可以解释为什么类固醇不见效,指甲生长不佳
Explains why the steroids aren't working.,Poor fingernail growth.
指甲难看的人多得是
A lot of people have bad fingernails.
三个器官系统同时衰竭的人就不多了
A lot of people don't have three organ systems,shutting down.
血管把癌细胞输送到身体各处
Her blood vessels are taking this,thing everywhere.
需要做全身性放疗
She needs total body radiation.
只有确诊了以后我们才能对症施药
We can't do anything until we can confirm--
做化学免疫分析需要花一周时间
running those immuno-chemistries could,take a week.
- 那时她已经是死人一个,- 不能说明放疗更加安全
- She'll be dead by the time--,- that doesn't make radiation any safer.
好吧 假设Chase和Cameron是对的
Okay,suppose chase and cameron are right.
假设这是自体免疫病
Suppose it's an autoimmune disease.
全身性放疗的最大危险是什么?
What's the biggest danger of total,body radiation?
抑制免疫系统
It suppresses the immune system,
这正是我们用类固醇要的效果
which is what we're trying to do,with the steroids anyway.
我一般不会初次约会就献身,但我不得不说这很刺激
I don't usually put out on my first date,,but I've gotta say that is a rad move.
让她把同意书签了 开始放疗
Get her consent.Start the radiation.
病人不是太喜欢我
The patient is not too thrilled with me.
那让我来弄吧
I'll get her consent.
Foreman有性格上的问题,所以你要插上一脚?
Foreman's gota personality issue,,so you're gonnastep in?
对于不喜欢Foreman的病人 我兴致浓厚
A patient doesn't like foreman.I'm interested.
疲劳 脱发 可能会有肺部损伤 不孕
Fatigue, hair loss,possibility of,damage to the lungs,infertility.
所有放疗可能导致的副作用
All possible side effects of radiation.
你为什么不喜欢Foreman医生?
Why don't you like dr. Foreman?
他自视甚高
He thinks he's better than he is.
- 那么他如何呢?,- 我不清楚
- How good is he?,- I don't know.
我们可以谈回我的病情么?
Can we get back to what's wrong with me?
在将来有很微小的可能会得白血病
There's a small possibility of leukemia,sometime in the future.
不值一提
Hardly worth mentioning.
如果你不清楚他到底如何,那么自视甚高也无从谈起
You can't say that he think she's better than he,is if you don't know how good he is.
- 他认为没人比他好,- 我啊
- Now one's as good as he thinks he is.,- I am.
你还可能会得白内障
You might also get cataracts.
签这里
Sign here.
我糊涂了
I don't know.
你是在告诉我这有多危险
You're telling me how dangerous this is.
这是在救你的命
We're saving your life.
就是那么牛 签那里
We're that good.Sign there.
我决定不下来
I can't decide.
你用铅笔还是钢笔
Would you rather a pencil or a pen?
谁演的007更出色?,肖恩·康纳利还是丹尼尔·克雷格
Who's the better james bond,,sean connery or daniel craig?
- 甚至不需要动脑判断,- 又来了
- Now,see,that's not even a decision.,- It's happening again.
我没 没办法
I can't--I can't--
我 没办法--
I...can't--
加大血液稀释剂剂量,把她送到放射科
Up her blood thinners,and get her down to radiology.
病情发作 20分钟后就会恢复正常
The attack will be over in 20 minutes.
到时她会在这上面签字
Then she'll want to sign this.
昨晚Bonnie给我打电话讨论狗的事
Bonnie called last night to talk about the dog.
中间谈到了你
Your name came up.
天哪 你牙齿怎么还健在?
Good lord,how do you still have teeth?
她是新泽西最差的房地产经纪人
She's the worst realtor in new jersey.
这算什么 战争白热化?
What is this,escalation?
我跟Cuddy出去 你就去搞我前妻?
I go out with cuddy,you hook up with my ex?
我甚至不明白你用意何在
I don't even know what that's designed to do.
你上瘾了
You're an addict.
我要把你从自我中拯救出来
I'm saving you from yourself.
通过买套公寓?谢谢了
By condo shopping?Thank you.
如果我能找出你问题在哪里
If I can figure out where you keep going wrong,
就可以未雨绸缪,免得Cuddy成为第四任前Wilson太太
then I can nip this cuddy thing in the bud,before she becomes the fourth ex-mrs. Wilson.
没错 我还担心没法阻止事态发展呢
Yes, I was worried there was no way,to stop that train.
你得跟Cuddy做爱
You have to have sex with cuddy.
等等...为了阻止进一步发展?
Wait...to stop the train?
- Bonnie说我床上功夫不行?,- 啊?
- Bonnie said I'm bad in bed?,- Huh?
她说没动真情前跟你上床就好了
Yeah, she also said that if she'd slept with you,before she liked you,
这样她还好过些
then it would have made it easier to handle
当你一脸歉意 始乱终弃时
when you turned into the sorry bastard,who left her alone.
顺便说下 我跟她说你在浪费她的时间
I told her you were wasting her time, by the way.
你觉得这能阻止她?
You think that's gonna stop her?
这女人是新泽西最差的房地产经纪人
The woman's the worst realtor in new jersey.
- 感觉怎么样?,- 很虚弱 总要睡觉
- How do you feel?,- Weak.Sleeping a lot.
放射治疗后的正常反映
That's normal after radiation.
深呼吸
Deep breath.
还有点反胃的
A little queasy too.
我胃不舒服时总想吃香草冰激凌
When I feel sick to my stomach,,I always want vanilla ice cream.
能抚慰肠胃
It's soothing.
眼下最好只吸收流质
It's best to stick with liquids for now.
有杂音
I'm getting a murmur.
我的手臂疼死了!
Oh, my arm.It's hurting me!
拿掉它!拿掉它!
Take it off!Take it off!
天 我的...
Oh, my god, oh, my--
疼痛是个问题
pain is the issue.
血压袖带造成的压力就让她尖叫
Just the pressure of the bp cuff was enough,to start her screaming.
这不是癌症 感觉像...
That's not cancer.It sounds like--
感觉像她得了败血病
sounds like she's septic.
很多原因会导致疼痛
A lot of things can cause pain.
有多痛?
How much pain?
疼痛过于强烈
Too much.
这不是癌症 也不是自体免疫病
It's not cancer.It's not autoimmune.
是感染 而我们破坏了她的免疫系统
It's an infection,and we fried her immune system.
但她没有高烧 腰椎穿刺没问题
but she had no fever, lp was clear.
做个回波检测 确认是否感染了心脏
Do an echo to confirm it's in the heart.
然后我会告诉病人 我们害死了她
And then I'll tell our patient,that we just killed her.
我去告诉她
I'll tell her.
你一直没回我电话
You haven't been returning my phone calls.
- 我很忙,- 好吧
- I'm busy.,- Well--
如果今天下午你能抽出半小时
but if you have half an hour,a little later this afternoon,
离这里十分钟路程有套公寓
I just found this unit,ten minutes from here.
还没供应出售
It hasn't been on the market yet.
我不想买公寓
I'm off the market for condos.
James说对了?
James was right?
我想做你的生意根本是痴人说梦
I never had the teeniest chance,of selling you anything.
他当然说得对
Of course he was right.
就算你们离婚了,Wilson还是不停给你好建议
Wilson doesn't stop giving good advice,just 'cause you're divorced.
他情不自禁要跟前妻们友好相处
He's compulsive about remaining on good terms,with his exes.
想知道为什么我给狗取名Hector吗?
Do you want to know why I named that dog hector?
不想 保持神秘吧
No, let's keep it a mystery.
他还是幼犬的时候 脾气就超坏
Because even when he was a puppy,,he was the worst-tempered dog we'd ever seen.
他进行过入室训练
He was supposed to be house trained.
可每天早上还是在地毯上撒尿
He'd pee on the carpet every morning.
有人来 他啃他们的脚脖子
When we had people over,,he had to nip at their ankles.
"Hector尿地毯"的字母重新组合,就变成了Greg House医生
"Hector does go rug"is an anagram,for dr. Greg house.
我新婚时对你就这样恨之入骨
That's how early in the marriage I resented you.
我白送你们一套餐具了
Did I ever waste money on that place setting.
至少James伤害我后 会心怀内疚
James at least had the decency,feel guilty when he hurt me.
但我没伤害你
Whereas I didn't hurt you.
我都没娶你 明智地避免了这样的时刻
I didn't even marry you,cleverly hoping,to avoid moments like this one.
你总是需要他 他也总是支持你
You always needed him,,and he was always there for you!
你再对我喊 就得和我做爱补偿
If you keep yelling,,I think you'll owe me sex.
你知道他妻子在家里等他 可你满不在乎
You knew he had a wife waiting at home--,you didn't care.
不是说你破坏了这段婚姻,可你袖手旁观
I'm not saying you broke up the marriage,,but you didn't help.
首先 "Hector尿地毯"这个组合用的很烂
First, "hector does go rug" is a lame anagram.
想对Gregory House更好地进行重组吗?,"超级自负 对不起"
You want a better one for gregory house?,"Huge ego, sorry."
其次 换个行业吧
Second, find a new career.
如果让别人决定日程安排,就永远别想卖掉东西
You're never gonna sell anybody,if you let them control the agenda.
再者 我没欠你任何东西 我不是Wilson
Third, I don't owe you anything--,I'm not wilson.
我可不会为了讨好你而去买房子
I'm not gonna buy a condo just to,make you feel better.
- 你还好吗?,- 是的
- you okay?,- Yeah.
告诉我该怎么做
Tell me how to do this.
House说人们感谢你...
House says people thank you after--
没有模式可循
it's not typical.
我害死了这个女人
I already killed this woman.
现在我能做的就是别再犯错
All I can do now is not make any more mistakes.
首先 别以为你可以将伤害减到最低
First of all,stop thinking,you can minimize the hurt.
很多人都害怕死亡
A lot of people are afraid of the word "dying."
如果你为此过于谨慎 她就无法理解你
If you pussyfoot around it,,she is not gonna read your mind.
- 好吧,- 不 不是
- Okay.,- No, it's not.
你看着她时 会自然而然地想转变话题
When you look in her face,,you're gonna feel the instinct to temporize.
- 克服它,- 好的
- Crush it.,- Yeah.
然后等 给她时间接受这个消息
Then wait.Give her time to process the news.
让她知道你会陪伴她经历一切
Let her know you'll be with her,through all of it.
等到她不愿再想 目光重新与你相遇
Wait till she's done thinking,,till she meets your eyes again.
然后 当时机合适 碰触她
Then, if you feel it's appropriate,,you can touch her.
也许像这样握着她手臂
Maybe put your hand on her arm like this.
让她知道还有人跟她心手相连
Let her know she's still connected,to another human being.
你这办法很科学
You've got this down to a science.
你吓坏了
You're freaking out.
- 我告诉你了,- 满足她的需要
- I told you--,- give her what she needs.
她不需要一个因为做出错误决定
What she doesn't need is a doctor,who's not there with her
而弃她不顾的医生
because he made the wrong call.
你吓坏了 你理应如此
You are freaking out.,You should be freaking out.
我不会让她看出来的
I won't let her see it.
让她看出来吧
Let her see it.
怎么不戴面罩?
Hey.How come no mask?
我们认为...你受到了感染
We think...you have an infection.
放射治疗没用吗?
Didn't the radiation work?
它没有起到预想的作用
It didn't do what it was supposed to do.
你要死了
You're dying.
你是说 情况很严重 某天我会...
What--you mean, like,things are bad,,and someday I'm gonna--
还有多少时间?
how much time?
How much time?
- 不能确定,- 一年?
- We can't know exactly.,- A year?
- 不到一年?,- 不到24小时
- Less than a year?,- Less than 24 hours.
我不明白
I don't understand.
为什么告诉我这个 吓唬我?
Why are you saying this to,me?You trying to scare me?
- 你为什么这么做?,- 对不起 这是事实
-Why would you do that?,-I'm sorry, it's true.
这癌症这么厉害?,昨天你还认为我有机会
How bad is this cancer?,Yesterday you thought I had a chance.
你得的不是癌症
You don't have cancer.
你受到了感染
You came in with an infection.
- 我们没有查出来,- 什么感染?
-We didn't catch it.,-What kind of infection?
这不重要
Doesn't matter.
放射治疗是最坏的措施
The radiation was the worst,thing we could've done.
破坏了你身体的抵抗能力
We destroyed the part of your,body that was fighting it off.
感染已经扩散到心脏了
It spread to your heart.
那给我吃药吧
Then give me drugs.
有治疗感染的药物
They have drugs for infections.
抗生素要结合免疫系统才能生效
Antibiotics work with the immune system.
但放射治疗瓦解了你的免疫系统
But your immune system is,nonexistent because of the radiation.
如果是心脏问题 那就给我一个新的心脏
If it's my heart,you can get me a new heart.
- 一直都有人接受心脏移植,- 这也无补于事
-People have heart transplants all the time.,-It wouldn't help.
你全身都受到了感染
The infection is everywhere.
已经回天乏力了
There's nothing anybody can do.
对不起
I'm so sorry.
我们通知了你的祖父母
We've called your grandparents.
别碰我!
Get the hell away from me!
滚出去 滚出去!
Get out!Get out!
你大概骨折了
I think it's broken.
没能戏剧化地解决一切
Nothing like a melodramatic,gesture to solve everything.
我们也错了 类固醇治不好她
We were wrong too.,Steroids wouldn't have helped her.
我不是没帮她,实际是我置她于死地
I didn't not help her.,I actually pulled the trigger.
现在你也无能为力了
There's nothing left for you to do.
- 你可以回家...,- 你不过想宽慰我
-One of us could go home with--,-you're trying to make me feel better.
没错
Yeah.
我害死了一个女人
I killed a woman.
难道你不觉得至少,我该有一刻感觉一团糟吗?
Don't you think it's appropriate that I,feel like crap for at least a little while?
这帮不了她
It won't help her.
- 他在哪儿?,- 去重症病房了
-Where is he?,-He went to the icu.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
准备做抽吸
Prepping for an aspiration.
我们还不知道什么感染...
We still don't know what infection--
- 这对她没用,- 这不会伤害她
-it's not gonna help her.,-It's not gonna hurt her.
好吧 会伤害她
Well, it is gonna hurt her,
- 可不会...,- 不行
-but it's not gonna--,-no.
只要几分钟 脓肿取样 再加上...
It's just gonna take a few minutes.,Grab a piece of an abscess,some pus--
你真的对此漠不关心
you really don't care.
你对她的死因真的漠不关心
You really don't care why she's gonna be dead.
- 她要死了 是因为...,- 什么?!
-She's gonna be dead because--,-What?!
到底哪儿搞砸了 遗漏了什么?
What did we screw up,what did we miss?
我得知道
I need to know.
你得等
You'll have to wait.
把她转移回她的病房
We're moving her back to her room.
做过全身放射治疗的病人得呆在重症病房
Patients who've had total body,radiation have to stay in icu.
重症病房帮不了她
Icu isn't gonna help her.
至少给她点私人空间
Let's give her some privacy.
你想干嘛?
What do you want?
想看看我是否按时死亡?
Want to see if I'm dying on schedule?
还是你想我说 没关系 我原谅你了?
Or do you want me to tell you,it's all right--I'm okay with it?
希望你原谅我
I'd like your forgiveness.
虽然我并不指望你的原谅
I don't expect it.
很好 这可不像你在超市推车撞到我
Good, 'cause this isn't like you ran,your cart into mine at the supermarket.
不是
No.
你祖父母还没到
Your grandparents haven't arrived yet.
如果他们不能及时赶来
If they don't make it on time,
你有什么话要我转达给他们吗?
is there anything you would like me to tell them?
我从不了解他们
I never really knew them.
想让我给你朋友打电话吗?
You got any friends you want me to call?
现在是深夜
It's the middle of the night.
他们可不是那种肯帮你翻身
They're not the kind of friends,you ask to help you move,
不介意看着你死
never mind watch you die.
我还有很多事没做
I never did much.
身后没有留下一男半女
No kid to leave behind.
当我死时 世界依然如故
When I go, the world's not gonna be any different.
对你也算是个慰藉 对吧?
Kind of a relief for you, huh?
关于我...你说对了
You were right...about me.
是吗 哪次?
Yeah, which time?
我...
I, uh--
我对你有成见
I had a problem with you.
但你也有说错的地方
But you were wrong too.
我做过糟糕的决定
I've made some bad decisions.
偷车 抢劫
Stole cars,robbed houses.
害死人
Killed a woman.
但后来我有了改过自新的机会
But then I got another chance.
我离开家上了大学
I left home,went to college,
走进一个截然不同的世界
entered a whole other world.
可我无法摆脱的某一部分总是在想
But some part of me I can't,get rid of always thinks
如果我不是最聪明的 不拿第一名
if I'm not the smartest,if I'm not the first,
不管我去哪里 人们都会想我不属于这里
everywhere i go,they'll figure,out I'm not supposed to be here.
他们会把我送回去
They'll send me back.
你知道这种事不会发生
You know that's not gonna happen.
你闯出去了
You're out.
我永远离不开那里
I'll never be out of there.
我念大学的最后一个圣诞节回家时
When I came home that last,christmas I was in college,
感觉房子小得容不下我
it was like the rooms felt so small.
我感到窒息
I was suffocating.
可当我在门口告别时
But when I was standing on,the stoop saying good-bye,
妈妈张开手臂抱住我
my mom put her arms around me.
那是
That was--
那是我最后一次感觉如此自在温暖
that was the last timeI ever felt at home.
我拉开你跟我的距离
I only put distance...between you and me
因为我知道我们之间没有距离
because I know there isn't any.
关于我你也说得对
You were right about me too.
针对我这类人的体制的那些言论
That stuff about the system,being against people like me.
我知道全是胡话
I know it's crap.
我是说 这没错
I mean, it's true,
可也是胡话
but it's also crap.
我没有准备好再试一次
I just wasn't ready to try again.
可我总觉得我还年轻
But I always thought I was young,
我有时间
I had time.
你不离开吗?
Aren't you ever gonna leave?
不
No.
以下歌曲"Follow the Leader",演唱者: Matthew Ryan
Song name: Follow the Leader,Singer: Matthew Ryan
出自专辑 From a Late Night High-Rise,http://matthewryanonline.com
Album: From a Late Night High-Rise,http://matthewryanonline.com
- 你好?,- 死亡时间 3:35
-Yeah?,-Time of death 3:35.
随你做什么吧
Do whatever you want.
*It's follow the leader baby*,跟随引路人 宝贝
*It's follow the leader baby*
*that's how it's gonna be*,命运将会引导你
*that's how it's gonna be*
*if you ever really want to get lost*,若你真想迷失自己
*if you ever really want to get lost*
*then follow me*,跟随我
*then follow me*
想买醉吗?
you wanna go get drunk?
不了 谢谢 我有文件要处理
No, thanks.I've got paperwork.
*Follow the leader*,跟随引路人
*Follow the leader*
听着 我不..
Listen, I don't--
我不知道我信什么 但是
I don't know what I believe,but
有时候我会想 有人在关注着我
sometimes I need to think there's,something out there paying attention.
所以当没人倾诉的时候
So when I can't talk to anybody,
我就跟上帝交谈 仿佛有人在倾听一样
I talk to god and pretend somebody's listening.
我们都错了 知道吗?
We were all wrong,you know?
甚至House也错了
Even house was wrong.
我知道
I know.
*So maybe it gets quiet*,也许空气变得寂静
*So maybe it gets quiet*
*and maybe it gets numb*,也许感觉全都失去
*and maybe it gets numb*
*at least then there's still something*,至少还有什么
*at least then there's still something*
*to share with someone*,可以和某个人分享
*to share with someone*
*follow the leader*,跟随引路人
*follow the leader*
取得家属同意了
I got your consent.
- 胸罩扣,- 什么?
-Her bra hook.,-What?
她被自己的胸罩扣刮伤了
She scratched herself with her bra hook.
因此引发了感染
That's how the infection got in.
金黄色葡萄球菌
Staph aureus.
她仅仅死于葡萄球菌感染?
She died from a simple staph infection?
加上糟糕的决定
That and some bad decisions.
我外面等你
I'll be outside.
回去喝点东西 然后睡觉 早上起来
Go home,have a few drinks,go,to sleep,get up tomorrow,
再重来一次 别再搞砸
and do it all over,only better.
如果想得蒙宽恕 去找牧师
If you need absolution,go to a priest
或救济穷人
or give alms to the poor.
随便选个能带给你慰藉的方式
Whatever ritual comforts you.
我害死了她
I killed her.
我也有份
Yeah, me too.
这不是说"哦 我早该想到"
This wasn't,"oh, I should have,thought of that idea sooner."
这不是简单的用药失误
This wasn't messing up a dosage.
我们看着疾病象火车一样冲向某人
We see a disease rushing,down on someone like a train,
却不能每次都把他们拉出来
we can't always get them out of the way.
事情不是这样的
This wasn't that.
不是
No.
你会再犯的
And you'll do it again.
对许多医生而言
For a lot of doctors,
一生只犯错一次
this would be a once in a lifetime mistake.
但我们不像这些医生
But we're not a lot of doctors.
我们救过的病人 比平凡医生多得多
We must've saved more patients,than the guy down the street.
可有一小部分病人 他能用常规方法拯救
But a few of the ones that he'd save,by doing what everyone else does,
我们会失败
we will lose.
所以你要给我讲数据
So you're giving me numbers.
因为数据不会撒谎
'Cause they don't lie.
我无法原谅你 Foreman
I can't forgive you,foreman...
因为没什么需要原谅的
because there's nothing to forgive.
你跟他说了什么?
what did you tell him?
无需内疚
That guilt is irrelevant.
- 去吃点东西吗?,- 不行
-You want to get something to eat?,-Can't.
家里还有条狗在等着
Got a dog waiting at home.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
我干了坏事 妈妈
I did something bad, mom.
- 我伤害了别人,- 这不是你的错
-I hurt somebody.,-It wasn't your fault.
- 是我的错,- 那么我原谅你
-It was.,-Then I forgive you.
我原谅你
I forgive you.
从你的脸庞我可以看出来...
I can see from your face...
你永远不会故意伤害别人
you'd never hurt anybody on purpose.
知道我是谁吗 妈妈?
Do you know who I am, mom?
是Eric
It's eric.
当然
Of course.
我大儿子也叫Eric
*'s boy's name is eric.